<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Bundler Blog</title>
  <subtitle>The latest news on Bundler</subtitle>
  <id>http://bundler.io/blog</id>
  <link href="http://bundler.io/blog"/>
  <link href="http://bundler.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Bundler Team</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>November 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/12/08/november-monthly-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/12/08/november-monthly-update.html</id>
    <published>2018-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-17T10:26:04+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the November monthly update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, we &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/04/an-update-on-bundler-2.html"&gt;announced the upcoming Bundler 2.0 release&lt;/a&gt; and shipped a few prerelease versions. As mentioned in the blog post, Bundler 2 will drop support for Ruby versions that are no longer supported by the Ruby core team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re feeling adventurous, you can even try the Bundler 2 prerelease by running &lt;code&gt;gem install bundler --pre&lt;/code&gt;. (You can even use the Bundler 2 prerelease on Heroku, with the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/heroku-buildpack-bundler2"&gt;Bundler 2 buildpack&lt;/a&gt;!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the less adventurous, we’re writing documentation furiously, and we will post a full Bundler 2 upgrade guide along with the final 2.0.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, Bundler gained 44 new commits, contributed by 10 authors. There were 331 additions and 150 deletions across 51 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started. Don’t have time to contribute, but want to support our work? Sign up as a member of &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; to help fund our work to keep Bundler working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>October 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/05/october-monthly-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/05/october-monthly-update.html</id>
    <published>2018-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-17T10:26:04+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the October monthly update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We released &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/blog/2018/10/25/announcing-bundler-1-17-0.html"&gt;Bundler 1.17&lt;/a&gt;, which ships a new &lt;code&gt;remove&lt;/code&gt; command (for removing gems from the command line), new command options, new events for Bundler plugins, and new environment variables. For a complete list of changes, check out the &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/v1.17/whats_new.html"&gt;v1.17 release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also announced our &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/04/an-update-on-bundler-2.html"&gt;new plan for Bundler 2.0&lt;/a&gt;, a new approach that we think the Bundler team and Bundler users will both be excited about. We’re planning to write more blog posts and documentation about Bundler 2, and push a prerelease preview for interested beta testers in the next week or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, Bundler gained 107 new commits, contributed by 10 authors. There were 473 additions and 156 deletions across 35 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started. Don’t have time to contribute, but want to support our work? Sign up as a member of &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; to help fund our work to keep Bundler working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>An Update on Bundler 2.0</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/04/an-update-on-bundler-2.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/04/an-update-on-bundler-2.html</id>
    <published>2018-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-17T10:26:04+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Colby Swandale &amp; André Arko</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past few years the Bundler core team has been working hard on a major release of Bundler. We’ve been solving problems that users have seen since Bundler 1.0 first came out, but weren’t able to release without breaking changes. At the same time, we’ve spent a lot of time thinking about how to release a new major version with as little breakage and as few surprises as possible. We’ve come up with a system that allows everyone to use multiple major versions of Bundler at the same time, and we think that system will make future breaking changes much easier to handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this post isn’t about that system. This post is about a new plan for Bundler releases, dropping support for old Rubies, and how long we will support old Rubies and RubyGems in the future. Every version of Bundler in existence fully supports Ruby 1.8.6+ and RubyGems 1.3.6+. Maintaining that support is a burden not just on the Bundler team, but has become a blocker for the ruby-core team to accept Bundler into Ruby itself. The ruby-core team only has the resources to maintain three minor versions at a time: the current release, the previous release, and security patches for the next oldest release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To refocus the efforts of the Bundler team on useful work, and make it easier to integrate Bundler into Ruby itself, we are adopting a similar support policy to Ruby: each year, we plan to release a new version of Bundler that drops support for any Ruby that is no longer supported. We plan to issue bugfixes as needed for each previous major version of Bundler, and if security patches are needed we will try to issue releases for the previous two major versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, today we are announcing a new Bundler 2.0.0 release. It should not break anyone’s workflows, and only contains changes that are “breaking” in a very strict and technical sense of the word. This is an exhaustive list of the changes from Bundler 1.17 to Bundler 2.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dropped support for end of lifed Ruby versions 1.8.7 through 2.2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dropped support for end of lifed RubyGems versions 1.3.6 through 2.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moved error messages from STDOUT to STDERR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be extremely clear: &lt;strong&gt;all applications and Gemfiles that currently work with Bundler 1 will continue to work with Bundler 2&lt;/strong&gt;. You will not be able to upgrade to Bundler 2 if you are using an older version of Ruby or RubyGems that has been end-of-lifed and is no longer supported. We will support Bundler 1.17 with bugfixes for about one year, and stop supporting Bundler 1.17 when we release Bundler 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future releases of Bundler, we hope to schedule future breaking changes with a one-year deprecation warning period, while listening to user feedback and doing everything that we can to keep existing applications from breaking. Keep an eye on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bundlerio"&gt;@bundlerio&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/blog"&gt;the Bundler blog&lt;/a&gt; to hear more about the future of Bundler as we figure things out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have problems or feedback, we want to hear from you! Head over to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/issues"&gt;Bundler issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; and let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Announcing Bundler 1.17.0</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/10/25/announcing-bundler-1-17-0.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/10/25/announcing-bundler-1-17-0.html</id>
    <published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-17T10:26:04+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Colby Swandale</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Bundler team is excited to announce Bundler v1.17.0, our next feature-packed release! Most of the changes in this release are the result of the work from our wonderful contributors whom we would like to thank. ❤️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few features we want to highlight:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="remove-gems-from-the-cli"&gt;Remove gems from the CLI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve added a new command called &lt;code&gt;remove&lt;/code&gt; that allows you to remove gems from the command line. Here’s a quick example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Gemfile&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'https://rubygems.org'&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'rake'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'json'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now remove a gem using &lt;code&gt;bundle remove&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;bundle remove json
Removing gems from Gemfile
json was removed.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bundler will then remove the &lt;code&gt;json&lt;/code&gt; gem from the Gemfile. There also is an  &lt;code&gt;--install&lt;/code&gt; option that will run &lt;code&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt; after the gem has been removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="https://github.com/agrim123"&gt;agrim123 (Agrim Mittal)&lt;/a&gt; for developing this feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-command-options"&gt;New command options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve added a few options that extend existing features and improve the overall user experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;--optimistic&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--strict&lt;/code&gt; options to &lt;code&gt;bundle add&lt;/code&gt;  that will add a version constraint to new gems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;--gemfile&lt;/code&gt; option to  &lt;code&gt;bundle exec&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;--skip-install&lt;/code&gt; option to &lt;code&gt;bundle add&lt;/code&gt;  to skip running &lt;code&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt; when adding a new gem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;--only-explicit&lt;/code&gt; option to &lt;code&gt;bundle outdated&lt;/code&gt; to only show outdated gems that are listed directly in the Gemfile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-plugin-events"&gt;New plugin events&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve added new events into Bundler for plugins. Libraries are now able to perform an action before and after each gem is installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to see plugins take advantage of these events, and enhance the user experience on top of Bundler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="https://github.com/jules2689"&gt;jules2689 (Julian Nadeau)&lt;/a&gt; for working on this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="bundler-home-plugin-cache-and-config-environment-variables"&gt;Bundler home, plugin, cache and config environment variables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users have been asking for a feature that will allow them to specify a location for Bundler to place any files/folders that it creates or downloads, but until now Bundler has been hardcoded to place all of its files into &lt;code&gt;~/.bundle&lt;/code&gt;.  To solve this issue, we’ve added some environment variables that (optionally) let you tell Bundler exactly where to put its files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To change the directory where Bundler will store all user-level files (which is &lt;code&gt;~/.bundle&lt;/code&gt; by default), set &lt;code&gt;BUNDLE_USER_HOME&lt;/code&gt;. To change the directory where Bundler caches downloaded gems and gem metadata (which is &lt;code&gt;~/.bundle/cache&lt;/code&gt; by default), set &lt;code&gt;BUNDLE_USER_CACHE&lt;/code&gt;. To change the location of the user-level configuration file (which is &lt;code&gt;~/.bundle/config&lt;/code&gt; by default), set &lt;code&gt;BUNDLE_USER_CONFIG&lt;/code&gt;. Finally, to set the location that Bundler will look for plugin files (which is &lt;code&gt;~/.bundle/plugins&lt;/code&gt; by default), set &lt;code&gt;BUNDLE_USER_PLUGIN&lt;/code&gt;. To see a more detailed description of the change and the reasons behind it, check out &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/pull/6024"&gt;the awesome pull request from @gwerbin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="and-a-whole-lot-more"&gt;And a whole lot more!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot more that we’ve added into this release. For a more detailed list of changes, check out the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/tree/1-17-stable/CHANGELOG.md"&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="upgrading-from-bundler-116"&gt;Upgrading from Bundler 1.16&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;gem install bundler&lt;/code&gt;  to upgrade to the newest release of Bundler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy this release. Happy Bundling!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>September 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/10/15/september-monthly-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/10/15/september-monthly-update.html</id>
    <published>2018-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-17T10:26:04+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the September monthly update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bundler team merged 29 pull requests, including fixes for nested &lt;code&gt;bundle exec&lt;/code&gt;, various bugs around choosing and updating gem versions, documentation improvements, and full compatibility with TruffleRuby. We also released versions 1.16.5 and 1.17.0.pre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also decided how to drop backwards compatibility with old Ruby versions, allowing us to resume work to merge Bundler into Ruby 2.6. We may or may not complete everything in time for the Ruby 2.6 release at Christmas, but we’re still working towards it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September, Bundler gained 73 new commits, contributed by 12 authors. There were 419 additions and 151 deletions across 40 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started. Don’t have time to contribute, but want to support our work? Sign up as a member of &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; to help fund our work to keep Bundler working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>August 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/09/10/august-bundler-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/09/10/august-bundler-update.html</id>
    <published>2018-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-17T10:26:04+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the August monthly update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the help of &lt;a href="http://github.com/eanlain"&gt;@eanlain&lt;/a&gt;, we shipped a new guide: &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/v1.16/guides/bundler_docker_guide.html"&gt;“How to use Bundler with Docker”&lt;/a&gt;. We also dramatically improved error messages when version requirements conflict, shipped a playbook for adding or removing core team members, and fixed some issues handling gemspecs with non-ASCII characters. We also merged a fix that could cause Bundler to &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/pull/6675"&gt;fail when trying to install a gem that has had a version yanked recently&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that code work, we also added two new contributors to &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/contributors.html"&gt;the Bundler team&lt;/a&gt;! Welcome to &lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/radiomorillo"&gt;Stephanie Morillo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/greybaker"&gt;Grey Baker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephanie has helped create new Bundler docs (like the troubleshooting RubyGems and Bundler TLS/SSL issues guide), and update existing ones. She’s also responsible for updating the Bundler contributor guidelines and trying to make Bundler docs more accessible to new contributors. We’re excited to have her on board, and looking forward to working with her more in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grey is the author of &lt;a href="https://dependabot.com"&gt;Dependabot&lt;/a&gt;, and has regularly contributed to &lt;a href="https://github.com/cocoapods/molinillo"&gt;Molinillo&lt;/a&gt;, the core resolver library that powers Bundler, RubyGems, and Cocoapods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total this month, Bundler gained 58 new commits, contributed by 10 authors. There were 334 additions and 54 deletions across 30 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started. Don’t have time to contribute, but want to support our work? Sign up as a member of &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; to help fund our work to keep Bundler working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
