<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Bundler Blog</title>
  <subtitle>The latest news on Bundler</subtitle>
  <id>http://bundler.io/blog</id>
  <link href="http://bundler.io/blog"/>
  <link href="http://bundler.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-04-28T16:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Bundler Team</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The new index format, Fastly, and Bundler 1.12</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2016/04/28/the-new-index-format-fastly-and-bundler-1-12.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2016/04/28/the-new-index-format-fastly-and-bundler-1-12.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-28T16:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2016-04-28T20:29:13-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>André Arko</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new version of Bundler has arrived! With 1.12, we’re shipping one huge change and several smaller changes—the short version is that Bundler is getting faster and more capable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-new-index-format"&gt;The new index format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest change landing in this release is &lt;a href="http://andre.arko.net/2014/03/28/the-new-rubygems-index-format/"&gt;the fabled new index format&lt;/a&gt;, which has been in development for over two years. It has required significant work on Bundler and the Bundler API webapp, but it also lays the foundation for years of speed, stability, and security. In addition to the speed increases provided by the format itself, we’re also serving the new index directly from the Fastly CDN. That means Bundler will be able to talk to a server located nearby, no matter where you are in the world. We expect that to make a huge difference, especially in Oceania and Africa. 🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="exec-performance"&gt;&lt;code&gt;exec&lt;/code&gt; performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of the new index, we also made specific improvements to the performance of &lt;code&gt;bundle exec&lt;/code&gt;. It now avoids running &lt;code&gt;Kernel.exec&lt;/code&gt; if possible, and only evaluates the &lt;code&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt; one time, instead of twice. Added together, these changes should speed up any &lt;code&gt;bundle exec&lt;/code&gt; command by around 0.25 seconds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="outdated-by-version-size"&gt;&lt;code&gt;outdated&lt;/code&gt; by version size&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another new feature is the ability to run &lt;code&gt;bundle outdated&lt;/code&gt; with the flags &lt;code&gt;--major&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;--minor&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;--tiny&lt;/code&gt;. Using those flags, you can limit Bundler to only show you new versions that are both allowed by your &lt;code&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt; and also meet the criteria of only changing the major, minor, or tiny version of the gem. You can combine them to get only minor and tiny updates, or even only major and tiny updates (but I have no idea why you would want to do that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="ruby-versions"&gt;Ruby versions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our final big feature is support for locking Ruby versions! That means that you can put &lt;code&gt;ruby "~&amp;gt; 2.3"&lt;/code&gt; in your &lt;code&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt;, and Bundler will save your exact Ruby version (say, 2.3.1) into your &lt;code&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt;. You can update the ruby version by running &lt;code&gt;bundle update --ruby&lt;/code&gt;, and that will update the lock to match your current version of Ruby the same way Bundler currently updates gem versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minor changes include adding support for Ruby 2.4, RubyGems 2.6.3, and support for the Ruby 2.3 feature of freezing all string literals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="changelog"&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We added a bunch of other small tweaks, features, and bugfixes, so be sure to check out &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md"&gt;the changelog&lt;/a&gt; for the entire list!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="updating"&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the newest version of Bundler, run &lt;code&gt;gem install bundler&lt;/code&gt;. If you have any issues, please check out our &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/ISSUES.md"&gt;issues guide&lt;/a&gt; and let us know!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Version 1.11 released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2015/12/12/version-1-11-released.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2015/12/12/version-1-11-released.html</id>
    <published>2015-12-12T11:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2016-04-28T15:48:34-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Samuel Giddins</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bundler 1.11 is here! Six and a half months after the last big release, we’re
finally ready to ship 1.11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s been a while, but there’s a pretty good reason for that. Over the
summer, the team was busy supervising &lt;em&gt;four&lt;/em&gt; Google Summer of Code students:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We made a significant amount of progress on the new compact gem index, which
ought to ship in 1.12 in the near future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We improved the Bundler website and online documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve created a solid base for Bundler 2.0.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We prototyped a new plugin system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Bundler Core team has spent a lot of time focusing on the
development experience of bundler itself. The bundler codebase is over five
years old, and contains code from over 400 contributors. That can make it
rather daunting to start contributing, and also makes it hard to ensure that
all of the code in bundler is up to the same standards (and is fit to last for
the next five years!). In order to make things more consistent, we’ve
introduced RuboCop (and thus a style guide), we’ve instituted a build bot to
ensure that &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; is never failing, and have decided to subject 100% of the
new code introduced to code review. This is a big step forward, and lets me
confidently say that this will be our best release yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That out of the way, what’s actually in this long-awaited release?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-features"&gt;New features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up, we’ve combed through a few years worth of bundler issues, and have
improved the error messaging for every single one of them. Our goal is to never
show an exception with a backtrace, and instead present a friendly and helpful
error message when things go awry – and we’re now pretty close to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dependency resolver has also seen a few updates. Continuing the theme of
improved errors, version conflicts will now do a better job of reporting what
versions of every gem have been activated, making it even easier to figure out
the best way to resolve said conflict. Additionally, resolution has been sped up
by over 25x in pathological cases. That’s a pretty nice win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ve laid the groundwork for resolving gems based on the current
version of Ruby.  Once the new index is rolled out, Bundler will make sure to
choose gems whose &lt;code&gt;required_ruby_version&lt;/code&gt; matches the Ruby you are running on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="bugfixes"&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real meat of this release comes in the bugfix section, however. Across
almost four hundred commits, we’ve squashed upwards of fifty unique bugs.
Meaning this version of bundler should be the fastest, most stable version we’ve
ever released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whats-next"&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier, this long gap between releases doesn’t mean we’re
slowing down development – quite the opposite, in fact! We’re actively working
on bundler 1.12 and 2.0 &lt;em&gt;at this very moment&lt;/em&gt;, and are incredibly exited to get
the new index into people’s hands as fast as we possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="updating"&gt;Updating&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install the last release of Bundler, you can run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
$ [sudo] gem install bundler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the details, don’t miss the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/v1.11.0/CHANGELOG.md#1110-2015-12-12"&gt;Changelog&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Version 1.10 released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2015/06/24/version-1-10-released.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2015/06/24/version-1-10-released.html</id>
    <published>2015-06-23T22:36:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2016-04-28T15:44:36-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>André Arko</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bundler 1.10 is out! In fact, Bundler 1.10.5 is out today, so we thought it was high time to let everyone know about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release comes with a bunch of new features: the &lt;code&gt;lock&lt;/code&gt; command, support for inline gemfiles in scripts, the ability to disable post-install messages, optional groups, conditional gem installation, dramatically improved &lt;code&gt;outdated&lt;/code&gt; output, and the option to force installed gems to be downloaded and installed again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://qiita.com/jnchito/items/a9907114bc56af67d0b0"&gt;日本語訳 / Japanese translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-features"&gt;New features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up, the new &lt;code&gt;lock&lt;/code&gt; command. Running &lt;code&gt;bundle lock&lt;/code&gt; will resolve the Gemfile and write a Gemfile.lock, but will not download or install any gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, for single-file scripts that still depend on gems, a &lt;code&gt;gemfile&lt;/code&gt; method is provided by &lt;code&gt;require "bundler/inline"&lt;/code&gt;. This method will not generate a lock, so be careful what gem versions you allow! Check out the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/lib/bundler/inline.rb"&gt;inline docs&lt;/a&gt; for details and examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you tired of being told to HTTParty hard? This option’s for you. Run &lt;code&gt;bundle config ignore_messages.httparty true&lt;/code&gt; to silence HTTParty for good, or run &lt;code&gt;bundle config ignore_messages true&lt;/code&gt; to turn off all messages forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who needs a jetpack future when you can have optional groups? The long-requested ability to create groups of gems that are not installed by default is finally here. Mark a group as optional using &lt;code&gt;group :name, optional: true do&lt;/code&gt;, and then opt in to installing an optional group with &lt;code&gt;bundle install --with name&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time as adding the long-awaited optional groups, we added groups that can be installed (or not) completely automatically! Provide a lambda or proc to determine if gems in the &lt;code&gt;install_if&lt;/code&gt; group should be installed, and they will be. Or not. For an example, check out the &lt;a href="/v1.10/man/gemfile.5.html#INSTALL_IF-install_if-"&gt;Gemfile&lt;/a&gt; documentation. The idea for this feature came entirely from discussions with &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/members"&gt;Ruby Together members&lt;/a&gt;. If you’d like to see more features like this one, or even suggest some of your own, &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/join"&gt;join Ruby Together today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not all! There are several more smaller changes, including better support for gems with native extensions on RubyGems 2.2. Check out the full &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/1-10-stable/CHANGELOG.md"&gt;1.10 changelog&lt;/a&gt; for the entire list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="bundled-with"&gt;BUNDLED WITH&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release also contains a change that has been somewhat controversial: Bundler 1.10 will add the Bundler version to the &lt;code&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the intended workflow involves only one lock change per Bundler version, the results in real life have been very frustrating. The &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; short explanation is that the problem will disappear once the entire team (rather than only part of the team) upgrades to Bundler 1.9.10 or higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the long explanation: Bundler 1.10 adds the BUNDLED WITH section to the lock, while Bundler 1.9 removes it. When a team includes some developers on 1.9 or older, and some developers on 1.10 or higher, it’s easy to end up in a situation with commits changing the lock back and forth. The simplest way to stop that problem is to upgrade to 1.10 by running &lt;code&gt;gem install bundler&lt;/code&gt;. When Bundler 1.10 or higher sees a BUNDLED WITH section, it will leave it in the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change turned out to be a lot more problematic than we were expecting because of the way Spring works. Knowing what I know now, I would have rolled out this change completely differently to reduce this problem, but it’s too late for that now. :/ We designed the change to only activate when you run an “install” command, like &lt;code&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;bundle update&lt;/code&gt;. If you just use &lt;code&gt;bundle exec&lt;/code&gt;, the lock does not change. We didn’t count on Spring, which runs &lt;code&gt;bundle install --local&lt;/code&gt; all the time in the background without notifying users. To stop that from happening, we’ve released a version of Bundler (1.10.4) that works around Spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last issue is that some developers refuse to upgrade from 1.9 to 1.10, for whatever reason, keeping the problem alive. To address that, we’re releasing a final update to 1.9 later today that will simply ignore the BUNDLED WITH section, rather than deleting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason that we made the change is pretty straightforward: It has been a long-term source of bug reports that users are often on a version of Bundler so old it won’t work for a project, but they have no way to tell. We’ve wanted to fix this by tracking the Bunder version in the lock file since right after 1.0.0 came out. Unfortunately, there was a bug in the 1.0.x lock parser that meant we had to wait until 1.0 fell out of use. We also need to start tracking the Bundler version in the bundle now because we plan to release 2.0 (with big improvements, but breaking some backwards compatibility).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point in the explanation, several people have then asked if we could just track the minor version, without the bugfix version. What if it was just 1.10? Would that give most of the benefits without the git churn? Despite this, there are two factors that made us decide to stick with patch level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, and most importantly, as soon as everyone is on 1.10+, the churn completely disappears. Version 1.10.1 will not change a lock that says it was bundled with 1.10.3. The absolute worst case once everyone has upgraded to Bundler 1.9.10 or higher is a single commit per version of Bundler, followed by no git churn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, Bundler patch level releases definitely fix bugs, and oftentimes those bugs are big enough to break &lt;code&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt; for certain subsets of users. Only tracking minor version would be similar to only tracking the minor version of Rails—it’s not really feasible to say “oh, you can use any 4.2.x version of Rails”, because the x allows security holes, breaking bugs, and other problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in conclusion, the change was never intended to be this disruptive, we’re doing what we can to reduce the impact, and the problem should be completely resolved by updating Bundler to 1.10 (or even the latest 1.9 release, if some of your team want to stay on 1.9).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the feedback, everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hello, Bundler 1.9!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2015/03/21/hello-bundler-19.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2015/03/21/hello-bundler-19.html</id>
    <published>2015-03-20T17:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2016-04-28T15:44:36-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Samuel Giddins</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A mere month and a half after the release of Bundler 1.8, we’re happy to announce our next act: Bundler 1.9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/v1.9.0/CHANGELOG.md#190-2015-03-20"&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/a&gt; for this version might seem rather short (and light on big new features), there is one cool thing to talk about: &lt;a href="https://github.com/CocoaPods/Molinillo"&gt;Molinillo&lt;/a&gt;. Molinillo is a new dependency resolution algorithm developed for &lt;a href="http://cocoapods.org"&gt;CocoaPods&lt;/a&gt; – the Cocoa dependency manager. Now, Bundler shares its dependency resolver – one of the most integral parts of a dependency manager – with CocoaPods, with the core logic being independently documented and tested. Molinillo was developed thanks to a &lt;a href="https://stripe.com/blog/stripe-open-source-retreat"&gt;generous grant from Stripe&lt;/a&gt; for the express purpose of being a generic dependency resolution algorithm that was sharable across different code bases – specifically CocoaPods and Bundler (and possibly even &lt;a href="https://github.com/rubygems/rubygems/pull/1189"&gt;RubyGems&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="dependencies-in-bundler"&gt;Dependencies in Bundler?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having dependencies inside Bundler itself is a bit crazy: Bundler is a dependency manager &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; gems, written in Ruby. How could it use gems itself? Well, it can’t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt;. But we can cheat a bit by shipping Molinillo’s source files inside the &lt;code&gt;bundler&lt;/code&gt; gem. This has its own challenge – what if a gem (such as CocoaPods), requires a different version of &lt;code&gt;molinillo&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;thor&lt;/code&gt;, which is likewise vendored in Bundler)? The solution is to prefix the top-level namespace constant in the vendored gem with Bundler’s own namespace. The upshot of this song-and-dance is that Bundler can share open source libraries just like every other gem!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="updating"&gt;Updating&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install the last release of Bundler you can run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
$ [sudo] gem install bundler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the details, don’t miss the Changelog!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bundler template moves bins to exe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2015/03/20/moving-bins-to-exe.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2015/03/20/moving-bins-to-exe.html</id>
    <published>2015-03-19T17:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2016-04-28T15:44:36-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Benjamin Fleischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/v1.8.0/lib/bundler/templates/newgem/newgem.gemspec.tt"&gt;Bundler 1.8&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/commit/ab3e21784c6c18702869c771fbe7ae23c82cc7c0"&gt;moves the executables directory in generated gemspecs from &lt;code&gt;bin/&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;exe/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight diff"&gt;&lt;span class="gd"&gt;-  spec.executables   = spec.files.grep(%r{^bin/}) { |f| File.basename(f) }
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="gi"&gt;+  spec.executables   = spec.files.grep(%r{^exe/}) { |f| File.basename(f) }
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that the Bundler-generated gems can use and commit binstubs,
such as &lt;code&gt;bin/rake&lt;/code&gt;, to the &lt;code&gt;bin/&lt;/code&gt; directory.  Only files in the &lt;code&gt;exe/&lt;/code&gt; directory
will be built with the gem.  Prior to this change, we would need to either not
commit binstubs or change the gemspec not to include all files in &lt;code&gt;bin&lt;/code&gt; as
executables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing that needs to be done for existing gems.  To modify an existing gem
to use this convention, we only need to move the executable(s), if any, into &lt;code&gt;exe/&lt;/code&gt;,
and modify the gemspec &lt;code&gt;executables&lt;/code&gt; directory to &lt;code&gt;exe/&lt;/code&gt;, as above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;exe/&lt;/code&gt; directory for gem executables frees up &lt;code&gt;bin/&lt;/code&gt; to be used for
&lt;code&gt;bundle binstubs rspec-core; bin/rspec&lt;/code&gt; and other libraries that have adopted this
convention, such as Rails, which installs the scripts &lt;code&gt;bin/rails&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;bin/rake&lt;/code&gt;, and
&lt;code&gt;bin/setup&lt;/code&gt; with all generated apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a new convention.  The current practice of both specifying &lt;code&gt;bin/&lt;/code&gt; as the
&lt;code&gt;executables&lt;/code&gt; directory and where we put binstubs and other development-only
executables such as &lt;code&gt;bin/rails&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;bin/setup&lt;/code&gt;, meant that Bundler-generated
gems with executables were quite likely to have these development executables
included in the built gem, and then installed along with the gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than make the gemspec template more restrictive by only specifying one
executable in &lt;code&gt;bin/&lt;/code&gt; as an &lt;code&gt;executable&lt;/code&gt;, the Bundler team has chosen to use a
different directory, &lt;code&gt;exe/&lt;/code&gt;, as the &lt;code&gt;executables&lt;/code&gt; directory in the template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change is just part of the evolving conventions in gem development.  RSpec,
for example, has had its executable &lt;a href="https://github.com/RSpec/RSpec-core/blob/v2.7.0/RSpec-core.gemspec#L19"&gt;in &lt;code&gt;exe&lt;/code&gt; since 2011&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of the kind of buggy behavior you might see when binstubs are
build with a gem as executables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="demo"&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight shell"&gt;bundle gem new_gem
git add .; git commit -am &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"Initial Commit"&lt;/span&gt;
bundle binstub rake
git add bin/rake; git commit -am &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"bundle binstub rake"&lt;/span&gt;
bundle
which rake &lt;span class="c"&gt;#=&amp;gt;  ~/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.1.5/bin/rake&lt;/span&gt;
cat &lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;which rake&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#!/usr/bin/env ruby_executable_hooks&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# This file was generated by RubyGems.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# The application 'new_gem' is installed as part of a gem, and&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# this file is here to facilitate running it.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nb"&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'rubygems'&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"&amp;gt;= 0"&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;ARGV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;ARGV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;dup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;force_encoding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"BINARY"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;respond_to?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:force_encoding&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=~&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="sr"&gt;/\A_(.*)_\z/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Gem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;Version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;correct?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="vg"&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vg"&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="no"&gt;ARGV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;shift&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'new_gem'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;load&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Gem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;bin_path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'new_gem'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'rake'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is found in the last two lines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'new_gem'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;load&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Gem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;bin_path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'new_gem'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'rake'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rake executable no longer uses the &lt;code&gt;rake&lt;/code&gt; gem. It now requires &lt;code&gt;rake&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;new_gem&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when I run rake elsewhere, I get the warning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight shell"&gt;Bundler is using a binstub that was created &lt;span class="k"&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;a different gem.
This is deprecated, &lt;span class="k"&gt;in &lt;/span&gt;future versions you may need to &lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;bundle binstub new_gem&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt; to work around a system/bundle conflict.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened because of the line in the gemspec that installed all git-versioned files in &lt;code&gt;bin/&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;  &lt;span class="n"&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;executables&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;grep&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sr"&gt;%r{^bin/}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;File&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;basename&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix our rake install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight shell"&gt;gem pristine rake
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# (In your gem folder, you may also want to run `bundle exec gem pristine rake`)&lt;/span&gt;
cat &lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;which rake&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#!/usr/bin/env ruby_executable_hooks&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# This file was generated by RubyGems.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# The application 'rake' is installed as part of a gem, and&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# this file is here to facilitate running it.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nb"&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'rubygems'&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"&amp;gt;= 0"&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;ARGV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;ARGV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;dup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;force_encoding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"BINARY"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;respond_to?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:force_encoding&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=~&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="sr"&gt;/\A_(.*)_\z/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Gem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;Version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;correct?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="vg"&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vg"&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="no"&gt;ARGV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;shift&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'rake'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;load&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Gem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;bin_path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'rake'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'rake'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix our gemspec:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;  &lt;span class="n"&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;executables&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;grep&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sr"&gt;%r{^exe/}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;File&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;basename&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or just delete the line altogether, since new_gem doesn’t have an executable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it did, we could continue to use &lt;code&gt;bin/&lt;/code&gt;, create the file as &lt;code&gt;bin/new_gem&lt;/code&gt; and
specify it as the only executable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;  &lt;span class="n"&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;executables&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"new_gem"&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or use the new &lt;code&gt;exe/&lt;/code&gt; convention, create a file such as &lt;code&gt;exe/new_gem&lt;/code&gt;, and not worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Announcing Ruby Together</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2015/03/19/announcing-ruby-together.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2015/03/19/announcing-ruby-together.html</id>
    <published>2015-03-18T19:56:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2016-04-28T15:44:36-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;All of the infrastructure used by Ruby developers today, including &lt;a href="https://bundler.io"&gt;Bundler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://rubygems.org/pages/download"&gt;RubyGems&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://rubygems.org/"&gt;RubyGems.org&lt;/a&gt; is maintained and developed by volunteers.  While it’s good that no one company controls resources shared by the community, it’s terrible that the only people who work on our shared infrastructure are doing so for free and in their spare time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; was founded so the community can cooperate to solve that problem. It will fund on-call rotations, maintenance work, and improvements to the &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/projects"&gt;shared, public infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; used by the entire community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll also provide &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/benefits"&gt;benefits just for members&lt;/a&gt;. To begin with, opportunities to connect and exchange knowledge, turning &lt;a href="https://rubybench.org"&gt;RubyBench.org&lt;/a&gt; into a fully-fledged community performance benchmarking resource, and tracking and reporting on important deprecations and security issues for members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The community that has grown up around Ruby is amazing, and provides many fantastic (and fantastically useful) tools that any developer can use. Let’s work together to make sure those tools (and the community) are the best that they can be, for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or your company has benefited from the free and open-source tools available in Ruby, support those tools by becoming a member of Ruby Together. Membership dues directly fund work that benefits everyone using Ruby, and are usually tax-deductible. Both individual and corporate memberships are available. &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/join"&gt;Join us today&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 80%"&gt;This post was originally written for &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/news/2015-03-17-announcing-ruby-together"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
