<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Bundler Blog</title>
  <subtitle>The latest news on Bundler</subtitle>
  <id>http://bundler.io/blog</id>
  <link href="http://bundler.io/blog"/>
  <link href="http://bundler.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Bundler Team</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>December 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2019/02/02/december-monthly-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2019/02/02/december-monthly-update.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-04T16:56:48+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the December 2018 monthly update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In December, Bundler reached two huge and exciting milestones. First, Ruby included Bundler for the first time ever, including Bundler 1.17.2 in Ruby 2.6. Special thanks are due to &lt;a href="https://github.com/hsbt"&gt;@hsbt&lt;/a&gt; for years worth of work integrating Bundler into the ruby-core test suite and keeping everything working and up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, Bundler &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/blog/2019/01/03/announcing-bundler-2.html"&gt;shipped version 2.0&lt;/a&gt;! It’s a big milestone, and the Bundler team is very excited to adopt a yearly major release cadence, to better match Ruby itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bundler gained 55 new commits, contributed by 7 authors. There were 225 additions and 63 deletions across 21 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started. Don’t have time to contribute, but want to support our work? Sign up as a member of &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; to help fund our work to keep Bundler working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>An update on the Bundler 2 release</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2019/01/04/an-update-on-the-bundler-2-release.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2019/01/04/an-update-on-the-bundler-2-release.html</id>
    <published>2019-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-04T16:56:48+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Colby Swandale</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I released Bundler 2.0 that introduced a number of breaking changes. One of the those changes was setting Bundler to require RubyGems v3.0.0. After making the release, it has become clear that lots of our users are running into issues with Bundler 2 requiring a really new version of RubyGems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been listening closely to feedback from users and have decided to relax the RubyGems requirement to v2.5.0 at minimum. We have released a new Bundler version, v2.0.1, that adjusts this requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologise to our users for the disruption this has caused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="important-note"&gt;Important Note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bundler 2 introduced a new feature that will automatically switch between Bundler v1 and v2 based on the lockfile. This feature is enabled by RubyGems (only on versions 2.7.0+) which unfortunately has a bug when you run Bundler without the appropriate version installed. You may encounter an error message like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Can't find gem bundler (&amp;gt;= 0.a) with executable bundle (Gem::GemNotFoundException)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do, it can be fixed by installing the version of Bundler that is declared in the lockfile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cat Gemfile.lock | grep -A 1 "BUNDLED WITH"
BUNDLED WITH
   1.17.3

$ gem install bundler -v '1.17.3'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bug was fixed in RubyGems 3.0.0 but backports are now being prepared for previous major versions of RubyGems. We’ll let you know when they become available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Colby and the Bundler team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Announcing Bundler 2.0</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2019/01/03/announcing-bundler-2.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2019/01/03/announcing-bundler-2.html</id>
    <published>2019-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-04T16:56:48+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Colby Swandale</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Bundler team is excited to announce the release of Bundler 2.0 🎉!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release focuses on removing offical support of versions of Ruby and RubyGems that have reached their end of life, with a few other small breaking changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is the full list of changes to Bundler 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed support for Ruby &amp;lt; 2.3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed support for RubyGems &amp;lt; 3.0.0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changed the &lt;code&gt;github: 'some/repo'&lt;/code&gt; gem source to use the  &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt; schema by default&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Errors/warnings will now print to &lt;code&gt;STDERR&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bundler now auto-switches between version 1 and 2 based on the Lockfile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="update"&gt;Update&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve posted an update on the &lt;a href="/blog/2019/01/04/an-update-on-the-bundler-2-release.html"&gt;release of Bundler 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-is-version-autoswitching"&gt;What is version autoswitching?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version autoswitching means that Bundler will automatically run the correct 1.x or 2.x version based on your lockfile. This means you can have both Bundler 1.17.3 and Bundler 2.0.0 installed at the same time, and each application will use the version saved in your lockfile when you run &lt;code&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt;. Every existing application should continue to work using Bundler 1, even after you have installed Bundler 2 (or even Bundler 3 or 4, later on).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="installing-bundler-2"&gt;Installing Bundler 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bundler 2 requires RubyGems 3.0, so install that first by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ gem update --system
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, install Bundler 2 by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ gem install bundler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="why-does-bundler-depend-on-rubygems-30"&gt;Why does Bundler depend on RubyGems 3.0?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make Bundler’s user experience when it auto-switches between versions as smooth as possible, Bundler depends on particular features in RubyGems that were publicly introduced in RubyGems v3.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RubyGems is able to be upgraded to newest release using the &lt;code&gt;gem update --system&lt;/code&gt; command. See &lt;a href="https://guides.rubygems.org/command-reference/#gem-update"&gt;RubyGems Guides&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="upgrading-existing-applications-to-use-bundler-2"&gt;Upgrading existing applications to use Bundler 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bundler will never automatically upgrade an application to Bundler 2 without your explicit permission. If you are ready to upgrade an existing application to use Bundler 2, you can run this command and then commit your lockfile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ bundle update --bundler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="upgrading-new-applications-to-use-bundler-2"&gt;Upgrading new applications to use Bundler 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have Bundler 2 installed, new applications will use Bundler 2 automatically. After you run &lt;code&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt;, you can check the lockfile to see which version of Bundler your application will use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="can-i-use-bundler-2-on-heroku"&gt;Can I use Bundler 2 on Heroku?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes you can! The Heroku team has said they plan to upgrade the official Ruby buildpack to Bundler 2, but it will take some time. They have a zillion users, so that totally makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, you can use our &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/heroku-buildpack-bundler2"&gt;buildpack&lt;/a&gt;, which is exactly the same as Heroku’s but with Bundler 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Support for the Bundler 2 buildpack is limited. You are welcome to report issues at the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/heroku-buildpack-bundler2"&gt;bundler/heroku-buildpack-bundler2&lt;/a&gt; repository, but we can’t guarantee solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="major-releases-going-forward"&gt;Major releases going forward&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the release of Bundler 2, the core team now kicks off a new release schedule for Bundler: we’re going to aim for one major version release per year, so we can drop support for older Ruby and RubyGems versions around the same time that the Ruby core team does. Being able to stop supporting Ruby 1.8.7 is a huge relief!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="more-information"&gt;More Information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more questions, or want more information about Bundler 2, read our &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/guides/bundler_2_upgrade.html"&gt;detailed Bundler 2 guide&lt;/a&gt; for the full scoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="i-tried-to-upgrade-but-something-is-broken"&gt;I tried to upgrade but something is broken!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh no! Sorry about that. Please head over to our &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/ISSUES.md"&gt;troubleshooting guide&lt;/a&gt; and open a ticket so that we can try to fix your problem ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy this release. Happy Bundling!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— Colby and the Bundler team&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>November 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/12/08/november-monthly-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/12/08/november-monthly-update.html</id>
    <published>2018-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-04T16:56:48+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the November monthly update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, we &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/04/an-update-on-bundler-2.html"&gt;announced the upcoming Bundler 2.0 release&lt;/a&gt; and shipped a few prerelease versions. As mentioned in the blog post, Bundler 2 will drop support for Ruby versions that are no longer supported by the Ruby core team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re feeling adventurous, you can even try the Bundler 2 prerelease by running &lt;code&gt;gem install bundler --pre&lt;/code&gt;. (You can even use the Bundler 2 prerelease on Heroku, with the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/heroku-buildpack-bundler2"&gt;Bundler 2 buildpack&lt;/a&gt;!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the less adventurous, we’re writing documentation furiously, and we will post a full Bundler 2 upgrade guide along with the final 2.0.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, Bundler gained 44 new commits, contributed by 10 authors. There were 331 additions and 150 deletions across 51 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started. Don’t have time to contribute, but want to support our work? Sign up as a member of &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; to help fund our work to keep Bundler working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>October 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/05/october-monthly-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/05/october-monthly-update.html</id>
    <published>2018-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-04T16:56:48+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the October monthly update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We released &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/blog/2018/10/25/announcing-bundler-1-17-0.html"&gt;Bundler 1.17&lt;/a&gt;, which ships a new &lt;code&gt;remove&lt;/code&gt; command (for removing gems from the command line), new command options, new events for Bundler plugins, and new environment variables. For a complete list of changes, check out the &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/v1.17/whats_new.html"&gt;v1.17 release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also announced our &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/04/an-update-on-bundler-2.html"&gt;new plan for Bundler 2.0&lt;/a&gt;, a new approach that we think the Bundler team and Bundler users will both be excited about. We’re planning to write more blog posts and documentation about Bundler 2, and push a prerelease preview for interested beta testers in the next week or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, Bundler gained 107 new commits, contributed by 10 authors. There were 473 additions and 156 deletions across 35 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started. Don’t have time to contribute, but want to support our work? Sign up as a member of &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; to help fund our work to keep Bundler working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>An Update on Bundler 2.0</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/04/an-update-on-bundler-2.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/11/04/an-update-on-bundler-2.html</id>
    <published>2018-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-04T16:56:48+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Colby Swandale &amp; André Arko</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past few years the Bundler core team has been working hard on a major release of Bundler. We’ve been solving problems that users have seen since Bundler 1.0 first came out, but weren’t able to release without breaking changes. At the same time, we’ve spent a lot of time thinking about how to release a new major version with as little breakage and as few surprises as possible. We’ve come up with a system that allows everyone to use multiple major versions of Bundler at the same time, and we think that system will make future breaking changes much easier to handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this post isn’t about that system. This post is about a new plan for Bundler releases, dropping support for old Rubies, and how long we will support old Rubies and RubyGems in the future. Every version of Bundler in existence fully supports Ruby 1.8.6+ and RubyGems 1.3.6+. Maintaining that support is a burden not just on the Bundler team, but has become a blocker for the ruby-core team to accept Bundler into Ruby itself. The ruby-core team only has the resources to maintain three minor versions at a time: the current release, the previous release, and security patches for the next oldest release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To refocus the efforts of the Bundler team on useful work, and make it easier to integrate Bundler into Ruby itself, we are adopting a similar support policy to Ruby: each year, we plan to release a new version of Bundler that drops support for any Ruby that is no longer supported. We plan to issue bugfixes as needed for each previous major version of Bundler, and if security patches are needed we will try to issue releases for the previous two major versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, today we are announcing a new Bundler 2.0.0 release. It should not break anyone’s workflows, and only contains changes that are “breaking” in a very strict and technical sense of the word. This is an exhaustive list of the changes from Bundler 1.17 to Bundler 2.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dropped support for end of lifed Ruby versions 1.8.7 through 2.2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dropped support for end of lifed RubyGems versions 1.3.6 through 2.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moved error messages from STDOUT to STDERR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be extremely clear: &lt;strong&gt;all applications and Gemfiles that currently work with Bundler 1 will continue to work with Bundler 2&lt;/strong&gt;. You will not be able to upgrade to Bundler 2 if you are using an older version of Ruby or RubyGems that has been end-of-lifed and is no longer supported. We will support Bundler 1.17 with bugfixes for about one year, and stop supporting Bundler 1.17 when we release Bundler 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future releases of Bundler, we hope to schedule future breaking changes with a one-year deprecation warning period, while listening to user feedback and doing everything that we can to keep existing applications from breaking. Keep an eye on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bundlerio"&gt;@bundlerio&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/blog"&gt;the Bundler blog&lt;/a&gt; to hear more about the future of Bundler as we figure things out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have problems or feedback, we want to hear from you! Head over to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/issues"&gt;Bundler issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; and let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
