<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Bundler Blog</title>
  <subtitle>The latest news on Bundler</subtitle>
  <id>http://bundler.io/blog</id>
  <link href="http://bundler.io/blog"/>
  <link href="http://bundler.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-06-07T09:01:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>The Bundler Team</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>May 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/06/07/may-bundler-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/06/07/may-bundler-update.html</id>
    <published>2018-06-07T09:01:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-17T04:37:10+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the May Bundler update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, Bundler saw some bug fixes, &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/commit/9e87a1ca4b0c3002ac2774e4837234cef7e3ce08"&gt;a new &lt;code&gt;--skip-install&lt;/code&gt; flag&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;code&gt;bundler add&lt;/code&gt;, and a &lt;a href="https://bundler.io/v1.16/guides/bundler_plugins.html"&gt;new guide on writing Bundler plugins&lt;/a&gt;. (Thank you &lt;a href="https://github.com/jules2689"&gt;@jules2689&lt;/a&gt; for producing this guide!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bundler gained 9 new commits, contributed by 3 authors. There were 66 additions and 48 deletions across 17 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started. Don’t have time to contribute, but want to support our work? Sign up as a member of &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; to help fund our work to keep Bundler working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>April 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/05/07/april-bundler-monthly-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/05/07/april-bundler-monthly-update.html</id>
    <published>2018-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-17T04:37:10+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Bundler monthly update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, we fixed various bugs, worked towards releasing 1.16.2 with more bug fixes, and improved the way we hide Git URL usernames and passwords for the future. Bundler gained 28 new commits, contributed by 15 authors. There were 204 additions and 35 deletions across 22 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started. Don’t have time to contribute, but want to support our work? Sign up as a member of &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; to help fund our work to keep Bundler working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>March 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/04/09/march-bundler-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/04/09/march-bundler-update.html</id>
    <published>2018-04-09T15:01:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-17T04:37:10+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Bundler monthly update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bundler saw a variety of bug fixes in March thanks to our contributors, including &lt;a href="https://github.com/alyssais"&gt;@alyssais&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/koic"&gt;@koic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/MSP-Greg"&gt;@MSP-Greg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/nesaulov"&gt;@nesaulov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/kunruh9"&gt;@kunruh9&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/shime"&gt;@shime&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://github.com/greysteil"&gt;@greysteil&lt;/a&gt;. Fixes included &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/pull/6464"&gt;documenting the order Bundler loads config settings&lt;/a&gt; as well as fixing some &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/pull/6310"&gt;rescue calls that hadn’t specified error type&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, we published a &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/2053d65c974f55fc15196b3ad82d7749750b2a3e/doc/POLICIES.md"&gt;Bundler Policies&lt;/a&gt; doc to supplement Bundler’s existing Code of Conduct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming up next, we expect to ship bug fixes, push out a small feature release, and begin public testing on Bundler 2.0. In total, Bundler gained 60 new commits, contributed by 13 authors. There were 353 additions and 97 deletions across 47 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started. Don’t have time to contribute, but want to support our work? Sign up as a member of &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org"&gt;Ruby Together&lt;/a&gt; to help fund our work to keep Bundler working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>February 2018 Bundler Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/03/09/february-bundler-update.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/03/09/february-bundler-update.html</id>
    <published>2018-03-09T15:01:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-17T04:37:10+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Morillo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Bundler monthly update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bundler saw some fixes in February thanks to contributors &lt;a href="https://github.com/nholden"&gt;@nholden&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/voxik"&gt;@voxik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/cpgo"&gt;@cpgo&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href="https://github.com/deivid-rodriguez"&gt;@deivid-rodriguez&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://github.com/alyssais"&gt;@alyssais&lt;/a&gt;. Fixes this month included &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/pull/6288"&gt;a fix for certain instances of the “perhaps the lockfile is corrupted?” error&lt;/a&gt;, as well as &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/pull/6283"&gt;clear enforcement steps for the code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;. We also received &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/rfcs/pull/10"&gt;an awesome proposal&lt;/a&gt; to give the &lt;code&gt;add&lt;/code&gt; command superpowers, and add a &lt;code&gt;remove&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, Bundler gained 23 new commits, contributed by 8 authors. There were 291 additions and 59 deletions across 50 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing to Bundler? We always welcome contributions in the forms of triaging bugs, adding new features, writing docs, and engaging with the wider community. Visit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/doc/contributing/README.md"&gt;Bundler Contributor Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Making gem development a little better</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/01/17/making-gem-development-a-little-better.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/01/17/making-gem-development-a-little-better.html</id>
    <published>2018-01-17T15:01:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-17T04:37:10+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Hiren Mistry</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You may have experienced this before: you’re excited about a gem, and want to contribute to its development. You clone the gem repo and run &lt;code&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt; only to see the horror of installation issues or a failing test suite. What to do? Do you debug this unsure of how deep the rabbit hole goes, or perhaps leave it for another day as you’re short on time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently &lt;a href="https://github.com/deivid-rodriguez"&gt;David Rodriguez&lt;/a&gt; brought up the issue and explained one way to prevent this: by having gem repositories lock versions of gem dependencies like we do in app development. The team listened to his proposal and reconsidered the original motivation behind not locking versions of gem dependencies, the impact to gem developers, and whether those reasons were still valid today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with Bundler 1.16, the default for a new gem template created by Bundler no longer adds &lt;code&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt;, thereby allowing the lock file to be committed into the Git repository. Locking the versions of gem dependencies lets gem developers install a known working setup across different systems for development and save time by not having to debug broken installations. With a little CI configuration, gems can still be tested against new version dependencies (see CI recommendations below). We believe gem developers and the OSS community can benefit more by reducing hurdles for contributors. Some gem authors like Rails and Devise have been checking in the lock file into Git for some time now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change only applies to new gems created using Bundler by running &lt;code&gt;bundle gem&lt;/code&gt; to create a new gem skeleton. Bundler will not change the lock file’s presence in &lt;code&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; for existing gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank David for bringing this issue to our attention and implementing the changes to Bundler!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ci-recommendations"&gt;CI recommendations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are (at least) two ways to ensure the gem is still tested against the latest versions of dependencies in the CI, even after the &lt;code&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; is checked in to the gem repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="option-1-delete-the-lockfile-when-testing"&gt;Option 1: Delete the lockfile when testing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way is to delete the lockfile before running the test suite. This will test the build against the latest version of the gem dependencies, giving you a preview of what your users will experience when they install the gem. The easiest way to do this is to add one line to &lt;code&gt;travis.yml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;before_install: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"rm Gemfile.lock"&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means the CI only runs with the latest dependencies, and so the results may not match what gem developers see on their local machines. You can work around this problem by running the tests twice or setting up a Travis build matrix, to see test results for both, with and without a lockfile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="option-2-let-a-bot-handle-it"&gt;Option 2: Let a bot handle it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to make sure new versions are tested with the gem is to ask a friendly bot to update the &lt;code&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; and open a PR anytime one of the dependencies release a new version. Friendly bot options include &lt;a href="https://dependabot.com"&gt;Dependabot&lt;/a&gt; (by Bundler contributor &lt;a href="https://github.com/greysteil"&gt;@greysteil&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href="https://depfu.com"&gt;Depfu&lt;/a&gt;, and others. Having a separate PR for every version bump makes it easy to tell which gems and versions caused failures, if any. They also make it easy to update a version in the lockfile, secure in the knowledge that the tests have already passed with the new version.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Monthly update for December and yearly update for 2017</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://bundler.io/blog/2018/01/08/monthly-update-for-december-and-yearly-update-for-2017.html"/>
    <id>http://bundler.io/blog/2018/01/08/monthly-update-for-december-and-yearly-update-for-2017.html</id>
    <published>2018-01-08T17:09:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-17T04:37:10+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>André Arko</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Bundler monthly (and yearly) update! We’ve been writing monthly updates about Bundler for several years as part of the &lt;a href="https://rubytogether.org/news"&gt;Ruby Together monthly updates&lt;/a&gt;, and finally realized that we should be posting those monthly updates here, as well. Here’s to many more monthly updates to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed, &lt;a href="https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/news/2017/12/25/ruby-2-5-0-released/"&gt;Bundler didn’t end up shipping with Ruby 2.5&lt;/a&gt;. The Ruby language core team has yet to announce why they decided to remove Bundler a few hours before Ruby 2.5 was released on Christmas Day. Hopefully, we’ll find out the story there soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Bundler 1.16.1 has been released, with fixes or workarounds for all known issues. If you were waiting to upgrade to version 1.16, give it a try now! If you’re still seeing issues on version 1.16.1, please &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/ISSUES.md"&gt;let us know!&lt;/a&gt; We care a lot about fixing bugs and maintaining backwards compatibility, but we need to hear from users in order to know when bugs have crept in. &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In December, Bundler gained 59 new commits, contributed by 8 authors. There were 419 additions and 301 deletions across 36 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017, Bundler gained two new maintainers, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/0xcolby"&gt;Colby Swandale&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hsbt"&gt;hsbt&lt;/a&gt;. We shipped 21 releases total, which included 3 feature releases. Those releases included 1,392 commits, by 31 authors, with 21,892 additions and 5,860 deletions across 1,140 changed files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks especially to Bundler’s new contributors in 2017: Abu Nashir, Adam Wanninger, Adrian Gomez, Alessandro Dal Grande, Alex Taylor, Artyom Khramov, Ashish Sehra, Atsushi Yamamoto, Brian Christian, Daniel P. Clark, Daniel Ritz, Daniel Trierweiler, David Radcliffe, Dennis Suratna, Elia Schito, emsk, Eric Boehs, Erik Johnson, fotanus, Frederico, Frederico Bittencourt, Glenn Espinosa, Greg Werbin, Grey Baker, HippoDippo, Igor Bozato, Ivan Kuchin, Jack LaBarba, Jan Krutisch, Jared Kauppila, Jonathan Pike, Juan Barreneche, Julian Nadeau, Justin Myers, Kaycee, Keiji Yoshimi, Kerri Miller, leslie.wen, Mal Graty, Michael Deering, Michael Pitman, mpd, Noah Kantrowitz, Nobuyoshi Nakada, okkez, Olle Jonsson, Patricia Arbona, Paul Nikitochkin, Piotr Kuczynski, robcole, Robert Soly, Sebastian Nowak, Shayon Mukherjee, Stefan Sedich, Stephanie Morillo, Tejas Bubane, Tristan Hill, Urabe, Shyouhei, Wade Tandy, Will Jordan, and Zach Ahn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next month,&lt;br /&gt;
André and the Bundler team&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
